Summary

Mobile software developer and developer with around 10 years of experience designing and developing high quality software for a wide range of businesses ranging from Financial Services to Augmented Reality. Possess a strong technical background with a Masters Degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Florida. Started my career with a financial software development internship at Bloomberg LP in New York City in 2009 and since then have constantly sought to improve the design and quality of the software created while satisfying all business requirements smoothly in a future-proof manner. Personally I focus on simplicity more than anything else and have a goal-based approach.

App Showcase

Moneyou Go

• Mobile banking solution for NL and DE

2dehands.be

Largest Online Marketplace in Belgium

Blippar

• Visual Search and Augmented Reality

Layar

World's first major Augmented Reality Platform

 \mathbf{Jumbo}

E-commerce app for the Jumbo Supermarket

iPhone

March 2018 - December 2018

iPhone / iPad

June 2016 - December 2017

*i*Phone

June 2015 - May 2016

iPhone / iPad

November 2014 - May 2016

*i*Phone

February 2014 - November 2014

Recent Work Experience

Moneyou / ABN AMRO (Financial Services)
Freelance Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands March 2018 - December 2018

- Moneyou is a new challenger bank in the Netherlands and a part of the ABN AMRO family. I spent about a year there and helped them with their mobile frontends and also setting up a new serverless-lambda based microservice infrastructure on AWS. I was a part of both development teams and contributed significantly to the technical design for both. I also helped in conducting interviews and making a long-term analytics strategy for collecting data and getting the right information to the right people. Some of the features I helped design and implement are address book, spending wallets and transaction limits. Even ended up making a team and led them to win the internal hackathon!
- Markplaats / eBay Inc. (Classifieds)

 Freelance Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands June~2016 - January~2018

The eBay Portland team hired me in Amsterdam to manage the Belgium side of the eBay classifieds app portfolio. I helped them release the global classifieds app in Belgium as 2dehands.be with some features unique to Belgium (for example support for French and Dutch and integration with Adyen for payments). I did this singlehandedly for iOS and also managed communication between the engineers in the Portland team and the management for 2dehands.be in Amsterdam. Made many trips to the office in Portland to sync up with the engineering team there as well. Before the end of my contract successfully hired my replacement and trained him. Also, been a part of a two person team that won the internal hackathon two years in a row!

Layar / Blippar (Augmented Reality)
Senior Engineer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands November 2014 - May 2016

- Layar was one of the first AR companies in the world and they were acquired by Blippar later. I was part of a small but very highly skilled technical team of four people and we designed and implemented several core technical products like the Layar AR App, Layar AR SDK, Augmented Reality Tracking and Rendering, AR based walkthrough, Face Detection and Tracking, 3D Rendering on camera view etc. This was some really good technical experience and really enjoyed working here in a startup environment.

Previous Work Experience

IceMobile Agency

Senior iOS Engineer

Ebuddy

• iOS Developer

Simple Apps LLC

Owner

MicroStrategy Inc.

Software Engineer

Citisync.com

• iOS Developer

Bloomberg LP

Financial Software Development Intern

Amsterdam, The Netherlands February 2014 - November 2014

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2013 - January 2014

New Delhi, India

February 2012 - June 2013

McLean, VA, USA

September 2010 - January 2012

Gainesville, FL, USA

January 2010- July 2010

New York, NY

May 2009 - August 2009

Education

University of Florida

Master of Science, Computer Engineering

Gainesville, FL Class of 2010

Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective C, C, C++, Python, Bash, Javascript

Technical Skills: Test Driven Development, Automated UI Testing, Continuous Integration, fastlane, git, xcode, Software Security, Machine learning with Deep Neural Nets, Restful API Design, AWS Serverless Development

Business Skills: Agile/Scrum, Managing Expectations, Project Estimation, Converting Business Goals to Technical Requirements, Risk Management, Presentations and Demos

Other Interests

Pilot Training, Salsa Dancing, Spanish, Hiking, Travel, Poker, Pool and Snooker